Email: ivan.antipin@gmail.com Mobile: +(45)50173238

EDUCATION

Moscow Aviation Institute

Moscow

Master in computer science and mathematics

Sep. 1998 - Feb. 2005

Profile

Technology agnostic, passionate developer and experienced technical lead with more than 15 projects completed. I have deep understanding of software development and practical mind. Fluent at designing and implementing systems from scratch. Recognized by senior management as one of best performers in Nordea IT.

EMPLOYMENT

Nordea Bank

Copenhagen, Denmark

Chief IT Developer, Tech Lead

Feb 20015 - Present

- Designed and implemented highly available, horizontally scalable, long term storage with gRPC API. Tech stack: Java/Cassandra/gRPC/Kafka/Avro/Docker
- Reimplemented and led main Nordea trade storage and validation system. Designed API and scaled development. Led the team of 3 devs. Was rewarded as a significant achievement of IT in organization.

Tech stack: Java/Mongo/gRPC,Kafka/Docker

• Designed and implemented from scratch in-house replacement of 3rd party risk managing system. Frontend and backend. Led the team of 5 devs.

Tech stack: Kotlin/Kafka/Docker/REST/OpenApi/React/TypeScript

• Designed and led implementation of alternative for 3rd party "too-expensive" system for complex SWIFT message processing with a very tight deadline. Frontend and backend. Led the team of 3 devs. Was rewarded as a significant achievement of IT in organization.

Tech stack: Kotlin/Kafka/Docker/SQLite/REST/OpenAPI/TypeScript/React

• Reimplemented troubled API infrastructure for strategic static data system. Was rewarded as a significant achievement of IT in organization.

Tech stack: Kotlin/Kafka/Docker/CQEngine/REST/OpenAPI/TypeScript/React

• Replaced legacy Nordea major risk engine and sped it up more than x10 times.

Tech stack: Java/REST/Redis/Oracle/ActiveViam

- Worked across teams to promote best programming practices.
- Developed interview process pipeline.
- Influenced gRPC based API development in Nordea as an alternative to the REST for system-to-system communications.
- o Influenced and promoted Kotlin usage in Nordea as an alternative to Java.

Deutsche Bank

Moscow, Russia

 $Senior\ Software\ Engineer\ (AVP)$

Apr 2012 - Nov 2014

• Designed and implemented backend of risk management system.

Tech stack: Java/Oracle Coherence

Luxoft

Moscow, Russia

Senior Software Engineer

March 2011 - March 2012

• Implemented low latency price distribution system with zero GC.

Tech stack: Java/NIO/Multicast

Deutsche Bank Moscow, Russia Senior Software Engineer Apr 2005 - Nov 2010

- o Designed and implemented order management system with embedded matching engine. Reduced latency and throughput x5 comparing to previous system.
- Implemented declarative BDD framework (a-la Cucumber style that was non-existent at that time).
- Reimplemented price distribution component of AutobahnFX.

Tech stack: Java/JMS/Sockets/Oracle

SIDE PROJECTS

- Strategy back-tester for algo trading in kotlin, typescript.
- Telegram bot for technical analyses https://web.telegram.org/z/1072760314.
- AI research with python, pandas, numpy, scikit-learn libs.

SKILLS

- Languages: Kotlin, Java, C-sharp, Typescript, Python, SQL
- Technologies: Kafka, Docker, Mongo, gRPC, React, Avro, Protobuf, Cassandra
- Other: Algorithms, Computer Science, Machine Learning, Gradle, Bash, Unix, Git

RECOMMENDATIONS

Tam Freestone Bayes

Startup/Fintech CEO/CTO/CIO

Banking IT architecture, engineering and execution leadership; Oxon Cantab

Incisive and highly autonomous. Ivan is one of the most potent developers I know. He swiftly gets to the core of a problem, makes sensible, pragmatic technical choices, then produces - and as requirements evolve, rapidly iterates upon - clean, succinct solutions. While he has no difficulty in adopting new technologies when they are the right tool for the job, he defaults to simplicity in his designs. If something needs to be done well, and quickly, then ask Ivan to do it.

Anton Polyakov

Senior Engineering Manager at Google

I worked with Ivan and was his direct manager for a couple of years in Nordea Denmark. Ivan is a "10x developer". When I landed at Nordea I realized I needed a "break through" swat team to really move the needle and modernize core of our systems as well as seed the right engineering culture. Ivan was the core and founding member of such team. Capable, fast learning, bright and dedicated effective both at dealing with legacy systems as well as working on a cutting edge projects, with his help we went from an old PL/SQL core to an in-memory compute engine and from an old Oracle based warehouse with rigid and hard to evolve structure to a flexible document-based horizontally scalable data service with streaming API on top. Ivan sets and maintains a very high engineering standards bar but was capable of doing a well calculated compromises not imp/acting fundamental quality when we really needed to ship. Don't be misled by Ivan's direct communication style, it comes handy when you will need to get lots of work done and in no way it hinders Ivan's team player capabilities (he is a good team player and a capable tech lead)

Arasa Velaigam

Head of Subsidiary Accounting at Nordea

Ivan is an excellent developer and driver of technical solutions to very complex problems. His communication is efficient and he is able to quickly identify challenges, evaluate alternatives and solutions in an open discussion across varying user groups. I have witnessed Ivan continually develop his technical skills increasing his delivery capabilities and skillset. He is pragmatic and result orientated thus easily able to balance delivery timelines with changing requirements, priorities and infrastructure dependency issues outside his scope.